cocooncenter.co.uk 2019-12-10

# Privacy policy of personal data - Cocooncenter

### In full force and effect on 25 May 2018

In order to safeguard your personal data, Cocooncenter is committed to ensuring the highest level of protection for your personal data in accordance with the European and French regulations applicable to personal data protection.

Cocooncenter pays particular attention to protecting the personal data of its customers. We therefore commit ourselves to respect the law No 78-17 of 6 January 1978 relating to data processing, files and freedoms, modified by the European regulation 2016/679 of 27 April 2016 relating to the protection of personal data. The commitments, described in this Privacy Policy for the protection of personal data, comply with Cocooncenter's values.

For any information on the protection of personal data, you can consult the Commission Informatique et Libertés website: [www.cnil.fr.](https://www.cnil.fr/en/home)

## Who is responsible for the processing of my personal data?

The controller is the company that defines for what purpose and how your personal data is used. Personal data collected on the website cocooncenter.co.uk:

SAS COCOONCENTER   
Domiciled at: 1 rue de la Nau des Vignes, 51520 La Veuve

Hereinafter referred to as "COCOONCENTER"

## Why does COCOONCENTER collect my personal data?

COCOONCENTER uses your personal data mainly for the following purposes:

### Management of orders and customer relationship

We need the information that concerns you for the management of your orders and the consequences thereof (for example, deliveries, invoices, accounting and in particular the management of customer accounts, the management of the COCOONCENTER loyalty programme, the follow-up of customer relationship such as satisfaction surveys, management of complaints and after-sales service, and selection of clients to carry out studies, surveys and product tests).

### Payment of your orders

When you pay on Cocooncenter.co.uk, your payments are secure. COCOONCENTER does not collect your payment data but only a payment identifier and the first 6 and last 4 digits, as well as the type of your card so you will recognise the card that was used for payment. All of your bank details are collected solely by our PCI-DSS certified payment service provider to ensure secure payment process.

### The personalisation of our services and the messages we send you

Your data allows us to improve and personalise the services we offer and the communications we send you. For example, we can send you personalised emails or recommend products similar to those you have already purchased or consulted which match your interests.

### Fight against Fraud

COCOONCENTER may, depending on the results of the inspection carried out on the orders, take security measures, in particular it may request additional supporting documents. These measures will have the effect of suspending the execution of the order or cancelling it if the result of the analysis does not guarantee the security of the order.

### Customising online advertising (targeted advertising)

We may use data that does not identify you directly (technical identifiers or sociodemographic data) to adapt the advertising you view on our website or those of our partners. Your data may be cross-referenced with browsing data and other information collected in connection with our partner relationships, and alias created prior to use, such as your age group or gender for purposes of establishing your user profile and associate interest centres from which advertisements will be shown on behalf of advertisers. For more information and how to manage your cookies go to the "Cookies policy » page of the website.

### La connaissance client et les statistiques et performances de notre site

Nous pouvons utiliser des données pour mieux comprendre nos clients ou à des fins de statistiques pour analyser l'activité de notre site et améliorer les services que nous proposons. Nous effectuons des mesures d'audience, nous mesurons par exemple le nombre de pages vues, le nombre de visites du site, ainsi que l'activité des visiteurs sur le site et leur fréquence de retour.

## What personal data is collected about me?

### What kind of data?

We collect and process your surname, first name, address, email address, password, phone number, IP address, connection data and navigation data, order history, preferences and interests, products consulted, delivery incidents, and claims. Whether the data is mandatory or optional is indicated during collection using an asterisk. Some data is collected automatically because of your actions on the site, other information can be transmitted by partners.

### When?

We collect the information that you provide us with, especially when:

  * You create your customer account on Cocooncenter.co.uk
  * You place an order on Cocooncenter.co.uk
  * You are browsing Cocooncenter.co.uk
  * You participate in a game or contest
  * You contact our Customer Service
  * You write a comment
  * You consult our advertisements

## What communications am I likely to receive?

### Service emails

Following an order, you will receive several emails to enable you to track your order (order confirmation, information on the delivery of your package, etc.). These service messages are necessary for the proper execution of the orders and services you have requested. The receipt of this information is not related to the choice you may have expressed for the reception of newsletters and commercial offers.

### Newsletters

Following the creation of your account, and if you have accepted to receive our newsletter, you will be able to receive information and offers from Cocooncenter.co.uk by electronic communication. These newsletters allow you to keep up to date with Cocooncenter.co.uk news and offers from the Cocooncenter.co.uk brand you can take advantage of, on products similar to those you have already ordered or consulted on the Cocooncenter.co.uk website. We measure the opening rate of our electronic mailings in order to adapt them to your needs.

### Product alerts

We can provide email alerts to inform you of availability. These alerts keep you informed of the forthcoming availability of the product that interests you. The registration to receive alerts is done by clicking on the button "Inform me of the availability of the product".

## On what legal basis and for how long is my personal data processed?

The processing of your personal data is justified on different grounds (legal basis) depending on the use we make of the personal data. You will find below the legal bases and conservation periods we apply to our main procedures.

### Legal basis for the procedures

Among the applicable legal bases:

**The contract:** the processing of personal data is necessary for the fulfillment of the contract to which you have agreed.

**The consent:** you accept the processing of your personal data by express consent (checkbox, click, etc.). You may withdraw your consent at any time.

**The legitimate interest:** COCOONCENTER has a commercial interest in processing your data which is justified, balanced and does not undermine your privacy. With some exceptions, you can at any time object to a process based on legitimate interest by notifying COCOONCENTER.

**The law:** the processing of your personal data is made mandatory by law.

### Periods of conservation

Most of the data (e.g. your customer account information and order history are kept as long as you are an "active" customer and for a period of 5 years from your last activity (e.g. purchase, login to your account, or maturity of a contract or guarantee. Your data is then archived with restricted access for an additional period for limited reasons and authorised by law (payment, guarantee, litigation, etc.). After this period, they are deleted.

Purpose of the processing | Legal basis | Period of conservation on operational basis | Archiving | Useful observations  
---|---|---|---|---  
Management of orders for products or services | Contract | 5 years from the last activity | 5-10 years | A customer is active, for example, when he/she makes a purchase or connects to his/her account  
Using the cocooncenter.co.uk account | Contract | 5 years from the last activity | 5-10 years | A customer is active, for example, when he/she makes a purchase or connects to his/her account  
Customisation of our services (emails, recommendation of products on our site, etc.) | Contract | 200 latest views for on-site recommendation.  
3 years from the last activity prompted by emails |  |   
Sending messages by email or SMS (e-business prospection) | Consent | 3 years from the last activity | N/A | You may withdraw your consent at any time in your COCOONCENTER account.  
Targeted advertising/publicity profiling | Consent | 13 months from the depositing of advertising cookies | N/A | You can manage the advertising cookies in the cookie manager of the cookies information page, or report your objection to publicity profiling in your COCOONCENTER account at any time  
Prevention of fraud | Legitimate interest | until the verification and validation of your order | N/A |   
Retaining credit card data following a payment | Law | 15 months | Article L133-24 of the Monetary and Financial Code. | Your bank details are kept by a payment gateway provider  
  
## Who are the Recipients of my data?

### Transmission of data to subcontractors

The data that we collect may be transmitted to the service providers (subcontractors) on which COCOONCENTER relies for the performance of its services for the purposes mentioned above, for example, for the management, execution, processing, payment of your orders, as well as for marketing operations.

### For ad targeting

We inform you that we may share some of your non-identifying data with partners, such as customer profiles (socio-demographic data), cookies or technical identifiers, without their being able to identify you personally for targeted advertising purposes on our website or on third party websites (see also the cookies section).

### Improving our customer knowledge

To enable us to link up your different terminals (computers, mobile phone, etc.) and provide you with a harmonised experience on the different devices you use, we use tools for matching different devices. You can block it by resetting <https://www.criteo.com/privacy/>

You can also set your cookie preferences to manage cookies related to targeted advertising on the cookie information page.

## How to communicate my choices about the use of my data?

We are actively working to improve our Choice Manager available in your account to give you better control over the use of your data. 

**You can withdraw your consent at any time** or register your objection concerning the uses of your data as described above, via the dedicated links when creating your account.

### At any time afterwards

By email to [dpo@cocooncenter.com](mailto:dpo@cocooncenter.com)

By mail to: Cocooncenter – Protection of personal data – 1 rue de la Nau des Vignes, 51520 La Veuve FRANCE

### If you wish to proceed by email or mail

You are required to state your surname, first name, email address and mention the reason for your request and/or the right that you wish to exercise. To understand your request, we ask you to specify one or more reasons (e.g. stop emailing, objection to sharing with third parties for targeted advertising, deletion of my account, etc.).

You can also manage your cookies by going to the cookie manager on the cookies information page.

## What are my rights regarding the use of personal data?

In accordance with the regulations on the protection of personal data, you can exercise your rights (access, rectification, deletion, objection, restriction and transfer where applicable) and define the "post mortem" processing of your personal data by contacting COCOONCENTER by email: dpo@ cocooncenter.com or by mail: Cocooncenter - Protection of personal data - 1 rue de la Nau des Vignes, 51520 La Veuve FRANCE.

In order to enable us to answer quickly, we would ask you to state your surname, first name, email, address and, if possible, your customer reference. Some requests to exercise your rights (right of access) must be accompanied by a photocopy of an identity document bearing your signature to verify your identity and specify the address to which you wish to receive the response. A response will then be sent within one month of receipt of the request.

At any time over the course of the risk analysis conducted by COCOONCENTER in the framework of fraud prevention, you will be able to submit your observations. You also have the right to lodge a complaint with the Commission Nationale Informatique et Libertés (CNIL), including on its website [www.cnil.fr](https://www.cnil.fr/en/home).

Cocooncenter has a Personal Data Protection Officer (DPO) responsible for guaranteeing the protection of personal data. You can contact the COCOONCENTER Personal Data Protection Office at the following address: [dpo@cocooncenter.com](mailto:dpo@cocooncenter.com).

## Is my data being transferred outside the European Union?

You are informed that data concerning you may be transmitted for the purposes mentioned above to companies located in countries outside the European Union which have a lower level of data protection than in the European Union. Prior to the transfer outside the European Union, COCOONCENTER will take all necessary measures and guarantees to secure such transfers.

Transfers outside the European Union can be carried out in particular within the framework of our activities of data exploitation in connection with social networks and search engines (to the USA).

## What about the personal data of minors?

The services of COCOONCENTER are not intended for Minors, accordingly COCOONCENTER does not deal with data specifically concerning minors. For example, we do not create a marketing profile related to minors.  
It is up to the parents and any person exercising parental authority to decide whether their minor child is authorised to use the COCOONCENTER services.

## What use of data relates to Social networks?

The use of social networks and services of COCOONCENTER in relation to these social networks is likely to lead to the collection and exchange of certain data between social networks and COCOONCENTER. We invite you to consult the policies of personal data protection of social networks in order to obtain precise knowledge of the information which is collected by the social networks and which can be transmitted to COCOONCENTER in connection with its sites and applications as well as the purposes of use of your data, especially for advertising purposes. You will be able to configure directly on the social networks the access and the confidentiality of your data. COCOONCENTER collects on its behalf certain information and personal data related to your activity on the pages of COCOONCENTER social networks which use the services of social networks. This data is used for advertising purposes in order to improve our commercial relationship and the advertising addressed to you in order to offer you a personalised and social experience. The information collected by COCOONCENTER for its own account through COCOONCENTER applications, sites or services in connection with social networks are governed by these terms and conditions, and by the specific terms and conditions of the COCOONCENTER applications. **However, COCOONCENTER is not liable for the use made of your data by social networks regarding your own account.**

### "Plug-ins" and social modules

Our site uses "plug-ins" or social modules. These include little buttons such as "like", "share" by third-party social networks such as Facebook, Twitter, etc. which you will find on our websites. They allow you to like and share information from our websites and apps with your friends on social networks. When you consult a page of our COCOONCENTER sites (web or mobile) containing plug-ins or social modules, a connection is established with the servers of the social networks (Facebook, Twitter, etc.) which are then informed that you have accessed the corresponding page of the COCOONCENTER site, even if you do not have a Facebook or Twitter user account, and even if you are not connected to your Facebook or Twitter account. For example, if you are connected to a social network when you visit www.cocooncenter.co.uk, the social networks you are connected to may mention your visit to your account on those social networks. If you use the plug-ins (e.g. like), your actions can be recorded and published on your accounts in the social networks according to the setting of your social network account. If you do not want social networks to post your actions from plug-ins to your social network accounts, you must sign out of your social networks before visiting our site.

## What cookies are used for targeted advertising?

We use tracking technologies including cookies to tailor advertising to your needs and interests on our websites or those of partners. We invite you to consult the Cookies section for detailed information on the use of cookies and other comparable technologies and to find out the options available to you.

## Update our privacy policy.

This privacy policy may be updated periodically and without notice. Any changes will take effect immediately from the publication of the new privacy policy on cocooncenter.co.uk. However, we use your personal data in accordance with the policy in force at the time you submit the data. We will notify you of any material changes to our privacy policy and seek your consent where necessary and if it affects the purpose of collecting your personal data. In order to comply with the current regulations on the protection of personal data at all times, this privacy policy is reviewed annually by our services.

## Applicable law and jurisdiction

This privacy policy regarding the protection of your personal data is governed by French law and any dispute arising out of or in relation to it will fall under the exclusive jurisdiction of the French courts.

Last updated: 24 May 2018
